

Fatai Balogun

Full-stack Engineer

Phone: +234 8062 870 354

Website: https://fatai-balogun-portfolio.netlify.app

Email: <u>fattylee.remod@gmail.com</u>

Software Engineer with a broad set of skills applicable across different sectors and roles. Experienced Solution Architect and Full-stack Developer focused on smart product engineering using agile methods. With a strong drive for excellence through positive thinking. An enthusiastic achiever with a solid background in software development. Full-stack, well-rounded, multilingual, culturally aware professional with a unique ability to relate to diverse clients with various business needs. Highly skilled in solving technical, financial, and business problems for clients and other stakeholders. Committed to improving the quality of life via coding.

EXPERIENCE

Self Employed Jan 2019 - current

Code Mentor

- Adhered to social distancing protocols and wore mask or face shield at all times.
- Used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule.
- Taught the latest and in-demand skills in Web development to my students

Andela Talent Acceleration

July 2018 - October 2018

Software Engineer

I worked in a team of six developers for building Author's Heaven Project (A medium.com_prototype web app). I worked on a couple of features such as forgot password, password reset, comment to mention a few which drive the project to a successful completion. A handful of Tools were used such as Git, Github, Pivotal Tracker, PostgreSQL, Sequelize (ORM), Nodejs, Expressjs, Reactjs, Travis, Heroku to mention a few.

EDUCATION

University Of Lagos

Dec 2008 - Dec 2014

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SKILLS

Nodejs, MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, ExpressJs, TypeOrm, NestJs, Sequelize, Typescript, JavaScript, GraphQL, Restful API, TDD, Git and Github, Google cloud storage, Heroku, Object-Oriented design, Bash.

HTLM5, CSS3, Reactjs, React-hooks, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, Materialize-CSS, Material-UI.

Communication, Team-work, Attention to details, Adaptability, Agile Project Management.